Guide to the Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Alice B. Toklas Correspondence, 1946-61; Series IV; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - La Motte, Ellen, 1946 Jul 28 (Box 137, Folder 3155)
  - Lascaux, Elie, 1947-59 (Box 137, Folder 3156)
  - Laughlin, James, 1950 Jul 24 (Box 137, Folder 3157)
  - Leiris, Michel, 1948, 1954 (Box 137, Folder 3158)
  - Levy, Harriet, 1946 Jul 29 (Box 137, Folder 3159)
  - Lewis, Lloyd, 1947 Oct 29 (Box 137, Folder 3160)
  - Lord, James, 1946 Aug 29 (Box 137, Folder 3161)
  - Lounsbery, Grace Constant, 1946 Aug 6 (Box 137, Folder 3162)
  - Lutz, Mark, [1946] Aug 7 (Box 137, Folder 3163)
  - "M" general, 1946, 1948 (Box 137, Folder 3164)
  - Maratier, George, 1946 Aug 2 (Box 137, Folder 3165)
  - Marinoff, Fania, 1947, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 3166)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1947-50 (Box 137, Folder 3167)
  - Meulen, Pierre van der, [1946] Aug 9 (Box 137, Folder 3168)
  - Morel-Stäheli, M., 1946 Jul 31 (Box 137, Folder 3169)
  - Morgan, Miriam, 1946 Jul 30 (Box 137, Folder 3170)
  - Mowrer, Hadley, [1946] Aug 28 (Box 137, Folder 3171)
  - Museum of Modern Art (Box 137, Folder 3172)
    With draft of response by ABT on verso of one letter
  - "N" general, 1947, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 3173)
  - Pearn, Pollinger & Higham, Ltd., 1946 Jul 29 (Box 137, Folder 3174)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1946-56 (Box 137, Folder 3175)
  - Picabia, Francis, 1946 Aug 1 (Box 137, Folder 3176)
  - Picasso, Olga, 1949 May 5 (Box 137, Folder 3177)
  - Pivano, Fernando, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 3178)
  - Pope-Hennessey, James, 1948-[49] (Box 137, Folder 3179)
  - Pope-Hennessey, Una
  - Provincetown Players, 1954 Aug 4 (Box 137, Folder 3180)
  - "R" general, 1946, 1958 (Box 137, Folder 3181)
  - Rago, Henry, 1946 May 7 (Box 137, Folder 3182)
  - Raney, William, 1948-49 (Box 137, Folder 3183)
  - Ranke, Hubert, 1946 (Box 137, Folder 3184)
  - Ranke, Seppel
  - Reulos, [L.?], 1946 Aug 13 (Box 137, Folder 3185)
  - Reulos, Pierre, 1946 Aug 15 (Box 137, Folder 3186)
  - Revel, Pierre, 1946 Aug 12 (Box 137, Folder 3187)
  - Riba-Rovira, Francesco, 1946 Aug 29 (Box 137, Folder 3188)
  - Rinehart & Co.
    See: William Raney
  - Rogers, W. G., 1946-50 (Box 137, Folder 3189)
  - Rohan, Dilkusha de, 1948 Apr 18 (Box 137, Folder 3190)
  - Rose, Francis, Sir, 1946-55, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 3191)
  - Rose, Frederica
    Includes fragments of letters with drawings
  - Rosenshine, Annette, [1946] Aug 7 (Box 137, Folder 3192)
  - Roux, Eugénie, 1946 Aug 1 (Box 137, Folder 3193)
  - "S" general, 1946-57 (Box 137, Folder 3194)
  - Saint-Pierre, Jean, 1946 (Box 137, Folder 3195)
  - Saul, Milton
  - Sawyer, Julian, 1946 Jul 28 (Box 137, Folder 3196)
  - Schenck, Peter, 1946 Jul 29 (Box 137, Folder 3197)
  - Schneider, Douglas, 1946 Aug 23 (Box 137, Folder 3198)
  - Schwab, Raymond, 1947 (Box 137, Folder 3199)
    [Notes and clippings concerning conference on GS at Belley]
  - Scott, Anthony, 1946 Jul (Box 137, Folder 3200)
  - Selby-Biggs, John, 1946 (Box 137, Folder 3201)
  - Selby-Biggs, Ruth
  - Seillière, Renée, 1946 Jul 31 (Box 137, Folder 3202)
  - Sevareid, Eric, 1946 Jul 29 (Box 137, Folder 3203)
  - Sprigge, Elizabeth
    See: Forty-Eight Theatre
  - Stagg, Hunter, [1946 Aug] (Box 137, Folder 3204)
  - Stein, Rose Ellen, 1946 Jul (Box 137, Folder 3205)
  - Stein, Sarah, 1946 Jul 28 (Box 137, Folder 3206)
  - Steloff, Frances, 1947-48 (Box 137, Folder 3207)
  - Steward, Samuel, 1946-47 (Box 137, Folder 3208)
  - Sutherland, Donald, 1946-56 (Box 137, Folder 3209)
  - Sutton, William A., 1946 Jul 31 (Box 137, Folder 3210)
  - Sweet, Robert, 1946, [1950?] (Box 137, Folder 3211)
  - "T" general, [1946], n.d. (Box 137, Folder 3212)
  - Tavernier, René, 1946, [1948?] (Box 137, Folder 3213)
  - Tavernier, Genevieve
  - Taylor, Ellen Alix DuPoy, 1946 Jul 29 (Box 137, Folder 3214)
  - Taylor, Prentiss, 1946 Jul 28 (Box 137, Folder 3215)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 3216)
    Includes draft of response from ABT on verso of one letter
  - "U" general, 1949, 1955 (Box 137, Folder 3217)
  - Ullman, George, [1946] (Box 137, Folder 3218)
  - Ulrich, Dorothy, 1946 Aug 5 (Box 137, Folder 3219)
  - "V" general, 1946 Aug 12 (Box 138, Folder 3220)
  - Valette, André, 1946 Aug 1 (Box 138, Folder 3221)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1946-61 (Box 138, Folder 3222-3229)
  - Vauban, A., 1946 Aug 24 (Box 138, Folder 3230)
  - Villard, Léonie, 1946-47 (Box 138, Folder 3231)
    Includes preface to French translation of "Everybody's Autobiography", typescript, corrected
  - "W" general, 1946 Jul 31 (Box 138, Folder 3232)
  - Weeks, Mabel Foote, 1946 Jul 28 (Box 138, Folder 3233)
  - Weill, Henri, 1946 Sep 20 (Box 138, Folder 3234)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1958 Jan 15 (Box 138, Folder 3235)
  - White, Max, 1947-49 (Box 138, Folder 3236)
  - Whitehead, William, 1946 Jul 30 (Box 138, Folder 3237)
  - Whittemore, Thomas, 1946-50 (Box 138, Folder 3238)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1946-50 (Box 138, Folder 3239)
  - Wood, Myron, 1946 Aug 1 (Box 138, Folder 3240)
  - Yale University Library, 1947-49 (Box 138, Folder 3241)
  - Yale University Press, 1947-60 (Box 138, Folder 3242)
  - "Z" general, [1946] (Box 138, Folder 3243)
  - Unidentified, 1946, 1958 (Box 138, Folder 3244)
- Personal Papers, 1837-1959; Series V; 1; (3 boxes)
  Series V, Personal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by type of material
  - Account statements, 1940-41, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3245)
  - Addresses, ca. 1935, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3246-3247)
  - Advertisement (typescript carbon) for house to rent in St. Robert from Madame C. L. Roché, 1922 (Box 139, Folder 3248)
  - American Fund for the French Wounded
    - Certificate in Remembrance presented to Gertrude Stein, [1920] (Box 139, Folder 3249)
      [Includes letter of presentation from Isobel S. Lathrop]
    - Journal officiel de la Republique Français noting Gertrude Stein's volunteer work for the AFFW, 1920 Oct 22 (Box 139, Folder 3250)
    - Weekly Bulletin and circulars, 1917-19 (Box 139, Folder 3251)
      [Several issues of the Weekly Bulletin contain contributions by Alice Toklas]
  - Application for permission for Gertrude Stein to use an automobile (holograph in unidentified hand), ca. 1940 (Box 139, Folder 3252)
  - Autograph of Gertrude Stein on piece of paper, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3253)
  - Automobile authorisations
    - World War I, 1914, 1917 (Box 139, Folder 3254)
    - World War II, 1939-43 (Box 139, Folder 3255)
  - Bills and receipts, 1910-46, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3256)
  - Blue Book (directory of New Orleans prostitutes), n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3257)
  - Book jacket from Margaret Anderson's The Fiery Fountains. with title page inscribed to Alice Toklas, 1955 (Box 139, Folder 3258)
  - [Book of poems, unidentified, from Mildred Aldrich, given to the American Library in Paris], n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3259)
  - Book pages inscribed by, or to Gertrude Stein, 1902-27, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3260)
  - Book pages signed by Leo Stein, 1889-99 (Box 139, Folder 3261)
  - Book pages, signed: by, or to Mildred Aldrich, by Eugene P. Ullman, by Mrs. M. D. Stein, and by Brantz Mayer, 1837-1905 (Box 139, Folder 3262)
  - Bookplate: Gertrude Stein, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3263)
  - Bookplates: Leo D. Stein, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3264)
  - Burma Shave jingle booklets, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3265)
  - Calling cards: Miss Gertrude Stein, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3266)
  - Carbon work order book for automobile maintenance done at the Garage Raspail to Gertrude Stein's Ford, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3267)
  - Census receipt, 1945 Apr 9 (Box 139, Folder 3268)
  - Circular letters and announcements - World War II, 1942, 1944, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3269)
  - Citation - for walking dog without muzzle, 1945 Feb 19 (Box 139, Folder 3270)
  - Clippings saved by Gertrude Stein, ca. 1915-46 (Box 139, Folder 3271-3273)
    Includes: "Native Air" by Mabel Dodge Luhan, The New Republic 1925 Mar 3 Copy of New-Paris-York 1944 Sep 1 Copies of Le Petit Dauphinois, 1944 Articles by: Henry Phelan Gibb, W.G. Rogers, and Fanny Butcher Articles about: Ephraim Keyser, Ernest Wise Keyser, Janet Scudder, Ellen La Motte, Louis Bromfield, Lord Gerald Berners, Mabel Dodge Luhan, Bernard Faÿ, James Joyce, Francesco Riba-Rovira, "Mr. Bruce" & Mr. Frost," and women's suffrage.
  - Collection of notes and quotations, in Gertrude Stein's hand, ca. 1890s (Box 139, Folder 3274)
    [previously cataloged as "Q.E.D. - Notes and Drafts"]
  - College Course schedule with notes in unidentified hand, 1937 (Box 139, Folder 3275)
  - "Communiqué de son eminence le Cardinal Gerlier, Archeveque de Lyon," typescript carbon, 1942 Sep 6 (Box 139, Folder 3276)
  - Contracts, 1927-37, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 3277)
    [Includes contract for Virgil Thomson]
  - Copyright registrations, 1911-33 (Box 139, Folder 3278)
  - Declaration for change of address, 1943 (Box 139, Folder 3279)
  - Documents for approval of military travel for Gertrude Stein and Alice Toklas, 1945 (Box 139, Folder 3280)
  - Driver's licenses, 1916-46 (Box 139, Folder 3281)
  - Le droit de Varech by Georges Hugnet, printed copy with notes by GS inserted, and inscription from GH, 1930 (Box 140, Folder 3281a)
  - Envelopes, labels and wrappers (empty) written on by Gertrude Stein, Alice Toklas, or Thornton Wilder (Box 140, Folder 3282)
  - Estimate, detailed, from Mombazet Plumbers, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3283)
  - Excerpts from letters written by Lady Corbet [1915], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3284)
  - Fee table for food for soldiers (in Italian), 1943 Aug 17 (Box 140, Folder 3285)
  - Filing cards with notations by Alice Toklas, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3286)
  - Flag - United States of America - 7 red stripes, 6 white stripes, 45 stars, sewn [for? by?] Gertrude Stein, n.d.
    See: Oversize, folder 4328
  - Flags - miniatures of U.S. and Italian flags painted on paper (Box 140, Folder 3287)
  - Flowers - pressed and dried (Box 140, Folder 3288)
  - Fortune readings, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3289)
  - Funeral announcement for Jean Comte-Cent, 1942 (Box 140, Folder 3290)
  - Genealogical information about Stein family, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3291)
  - Gertrude Stein: Her Life and Work by Elizabeth Sprigg, printed copy annotated with commentary by Alice Toklas, 1957 (Box 140, Folder 3292)
  - "Gertrude Stein Interviewed by William Lundell," transcript of radio broadcast, with notes by Gertrude Stein, 1934 Nov 12 (Box 140, Folder 3293)
  - Identification cards, passes and passports, 1918-45, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3294-3295)
  - Insurance documents, 1924-37 (Box 140, Folder 3296)
  - Knitting directions in the hand of Alice Toklas (Box 140, Folder 3297)
  - Letter from Oscar Wilde to "My Dear Friend" [1891], printed copy (Box 140, Folder 3298)
  - Library card, Bibliothèque Nationale: Gertrude Stein, 1905 (Box 140, Folder 3299)
  - Luggage tag - French Line "Champlain", [1935] May 4 (Box 140, Folder 3300)
  - Maintenant special issue about the "Exposition des Indépendants", 1914 Mar-Apr (Box 140, Folder 3301)
  - Medaille de la Reconnaissance Francaise - certificate presented to Gertrude Stein, 1920 Sep 15
    See: Oversize, Box 169, folder 4329
  - Memo from President Roosevelt to Mr. Morley - facsimile torn from book, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3302)
  - Memorial card: Marthe Laval, 1916 (Box 140, Folder 3303)
  - Note by Lillian Goodman removed from unidentified book, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3304)
  - Note from Alice Toklas to Gertrude Stein, re: buying a hat, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3305)
  - Notebook (cahier) cover, unused, with printed Parole by Pétain, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3306)
  - Notes made by Gertrude Stein on airplane trip from New York to Chicago, 1934 (Box 140, Folder 3307)
    Includes: notes between GS and Carl Van Vechten on airline brochures and on verso of letter to GS from Elizabeth Dickson (1934 Nov 6); and unfinished postcard to Mr. Trac [Nguyen]
  - Notes (four leaves) in unidentified hands (Box 140, Folder 3308)
  - Pedigree for Basket II, 1938 (Box 140, Folder 3309)
  - Postcards - blank, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3310)
  - Poster advertising sale of properties from Mildred Aldrich's estate, [1928] (Box 140, Folder 3311)
  - Prescription slips, 1940-46 (Box 140, Folder 3312)
  - Printed pictures removed from books, n.d. (Box 140, Folder 3313)
  - Programs and invitations, 1929-47, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 3314)
    [One program signed by Warren Wirtz]
  - Prophecies, typescripts and transcripts (Box 141, Folder 3315)
  - Rail map of Bourgogne-Morvan [and] Jura-Lyonnais
    See: Oversize, Box 169, folder 4329a
  - Recipes, in the hand [of Alice Toklas?] and another, unidentified (Box 141, Folder 3316)
  - Rent receipt, 1936 Oct 15 (Box 141, Folder 3317)
  - "Schedule of Appearances by Miss Gertrude Stein", 1945 Dec (Box 141, Folder 3318)
  - Seal in wax: "Rose is a rose is a rose is a rose", torn from envelope, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 3319)
  - Sheet music: "La Chumbera", n.d.
    See: Oversize, Box 169, folder 4330
  - Sheet music: "The Trail of the Lonesome Pine", n.d. (Box 141, Folder 3320)
  - Shipping label: from S. Norbert to Gertrude Stein, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 3321)
  - The Signal Chorus, newsletter of the Signal Corps Renaissance in the Philippines, 1945 (Box 141, Folder 3322)
    Includes references to and spoof of Gertrude Stein
  - Sketch of picture placement for the walls of 27, rue de Fleurus, with note by Alice Toklas, [1914 Oct] (Box 141, Folder 3323)
  - Telephone directory page, Paris, listing Gertrude Stein, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 3324)
  - The Third Rose by John Malcolm Brinnin, printed copy annotated with corrections by Alice Toklas, 1959 (Box 141, Folder 3325)
  - Tobacco registration card: Alice Toklas, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 3326)
  - Transcriptions, holograph, of communiqués from M. Pétain, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 3327)
  - Transcriptions, holograph, of La Fontaine and Sarah Orne Jewett poems in unidentified hand (Box 141, Folder 3328)
  - Transcription, typescript carbon, of Abraham Lincoln's "Speech at Edwardsville, Illinois" [1958], n.d. (Box 141, Folder 3329)
  - Transcription, typescript, of statements by the Archeveques of Toulouse and Montauban on "la personne humaine", 1942 Aug (Box 141, Folder 3330)
  - Transcription, typescript carbon, of radio program reviewing The Autobiography of Alice B. Toklas, by Gerald Langford, WRVA, University of Virginia, 1933 Nov 14 (Box 141, Folder 3331)
    With letter forwarding the review to M. E. Brooks of Harcourt, Brace and Company
  - Transcription, typescript carbon, of Wendell Wilkie's "Report to the Nation on Global War and Peace" (Box 141, Folder 3332)
- Clippings, 1913-48; Series VI; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  Series VI, Clippings, is divided into two sections: General arranged chronologically and by topic; People arranged alphabetically.
  - General
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1913-18 (Box 142, Folder 3333-3335)
      See also: Oversize, Box 169, folder 4331
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1922-25 (Box 142, Folder 3336-3339)
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1926-27 (Box 142, Folder 3340-3341)
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1927-29 (Box 142, Folder 3342-3344)
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1927-29 (Box 143, Folder 3345-3346)
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1930-32 (Box 143, Folder 3347-3350)
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1933-34 (Box 143, Folder 3351-3353)
      Folder 3351 includes printed version of Stein's letter to Vanity Fair ["The native's return"]
  - Printed version, Vanity Fair, 1934 [Oct?]
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1934-35 (Box 144, Folder 3354-3362)
      See also: Oversize, Box 169, folder 4332
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1935-40 (Box 144, Folder 3363-3364)
    - About Gertrude Stein, 1941-46 (Box 145, Folder 3365-3367)
      See also: Oversize, Box 169, folder 4333
    - About Gertrude Stein, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 3368)
  - Gertrude Stein and Art, 1914-45, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 3369-3370)
  - Critical and biographical books about Gertrude Stein, 1917-42, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 3371)
  - Cartoons and caricatures of Gertrude Stein, 1923-34, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 3372)
  - Interview with Gertrude Stein - Yank magazine, 1945 Nov 11
    See: Oversize, Box 169, folder 4334
  - Obituaries of and in memoriams for Gertrude Stein, 1946-48, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3373-3374)
  - Pictures of Gertrude Stein, 1927-41, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3375)
  - Publication announcements of works appearing in anthologies, 1924-34 (Box 146, Folder 3376)
  - People
    - Anderson, Sherwood, 1925-42, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3377)
    - Berners, Gerald, Lord, 1936-37 (Box 146, Folder 3378)
    - Davidson, Jo, 1923-25, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3379)
    - Draper, Muriel, 1928-39 (Box 146, Folder 3380)
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1928-33 (Box 146, Folder 3381)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1927-34 (Box 146, Folder 3382)
    - Matisse, Henri, 1914, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3383)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1929-28, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3384)
    - Stein, Meyer, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3385)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1914 (Box 146, Folder 3386)
    - Wilcox, Wendell (Box 146, Folder 3387)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1934-44, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3388)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1931-32, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3389)
    - Various personnages, 1926-48, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 3390)
      Includes: Mildred Aldrich, Robert Coates, Bernard Faÿ, F. Scott Fitzgerald, Paul Rosenfeld, Edith Sitwell, Eleanor Steber, Michael Stein, Dolene Stein Block, Samuel Steward, Frank Swinnerton, and Parker Tyler
- Photographs, 1870-1949; Series VII; 15; (15 boxes)
  Series VII, Photographs, is divided into thematic sub-series, which are arranged chronologically or alphabetically, as they appear.
  - PHOTOGRAPH ALBUMS
    - Volume 1, ca. 1870-1920 (Box 147, Folder 3391-3439)
      Includes: GS with Stein family, GS as young girl, GS as young woman, GS at Johns Hopkins and Radcliffe, GS with student friends, GS on excursion to Woods Hole, GS with Etta and Claribel Cone in Vallambrosa, Fiesole, and Settignano, GS in San Francisco with Michael, Sarah, and Allan Stein, GS at Casa Ricci with Leo, Michael, Sarah, and Allan Stein, GS in Luxembourg Gardens, servants and concierge at rue de Fleurus, GS with Mildred Aldrich at her house (La Creste), GS with ABT in Venice, GS with nurses and war wounded in World War I.
    - Volume 2, ca. 1920-34 (Box 148, Folder 3440-3487)
      Includes: series of GS in countryside, studio shots of GS and ABT, GS in automobile, GS and ABT with Henry MacBride and the Princess of Sarawak, series of GS outside in the Bugey, GS and ABT on a picnic with Allan Tanner and Pavel Tchelitchew, GS with Bravig Imbs, GS with Paul Bowles, GS walking dogs in Luxembourg Gardens, GS visiting the Bromfields, GS at Bilignin, writing, with Basket I and Byron, and with visitors: George Hugnet; Madame Girard; Bernard Faÿ; George Maratier and Madame Maratier; W. G. Rogers; Pablo, Olga and Paulot Picasso; and Charles Henri Ford.
    - Volume 3, 1934-35 (Box 149, Folder 3488-3530)
      Includes American tour: GS on-board ship, GS at C.B.C., GS and ABT in Chicago: leaving plane; at the Art Institute; in home of Bobsie Goodspeed; with Charles Goodspeed, Fanny Butcher, and Thornton Wilder; GS at Harvard, GS and ABT in Springfield, Mass., GS and ABT at Bryn Mawr, GS at Hockaday School in Dallas, TX.
    - Volume 4, ca. 1935-40 (Box 150, Folder 3531-3594)
      Includes: GS at Chapelle Saint-Gabrielle, GS at the d'Aiguys, GS at the Palais Ideale; GS at Bourgeois-et-Priay with Bernard Faÿ and Charles Henri Ford; GS at Saint-Remy with W. G. Rogers; GS in Geneva with Mr. and Mrs. W. G. Rogers and Thornton Wilder GS at Bilignin, alone, with ABT and with: Madame Maratier; Mr. and Mrs. W. G. Rogers; Charles Henri Ford; Thornton Wilder; Pierre Reulos; Francis Rose; Hub Murphy; C. Mills; Henry and Clare Booth Luce; Père Bernardet at the Abbaye Hautecombe de Savoie, GS and ABT in England with: Lord Gerald Berners; Lady Rosebery; Lady Bridget Parson; Sir Robert Abdy; Lady Diana Abdy; and Robert Heber-Percy, GS at Faringdon House, GS at rehearsal of A Wedding Bouquet with Frederick Ashton at Sadler's Wells, GS with Lord Berners in Paris, GS with the d'Aiguy family after lecture in Saint Hyppolite, GS at 27, rue de Fleurus, GS with Pepe and Basket I and GS with Basket II, GS at 5, rue Christine.
      See also: Oversize, Box 170, folder 4335 for: GS and ABT at Bilignin
    - Volume 5, ca. 1940-46 (Box 151, Folder 3595-3655)
      Includes: GS at Culoz, KriKri Vaubon with goat, GS and ABT with William McKown and Olympe, the maid, William McKown with M. and Mme. René Tavernier, GS in Culoz after the liberation, GS with mayor of Culoz, GS and ABT with soldiers: boarding airplane; at Red Cross dinner; at Hitler's ruined home in Berchtesgaden; at airfield, GS with Donald Gallup, GS and ABT with WACS, GS with Basket II and Marie Laurencin, GS with Maurice Darantière, GS at art gallery, GS with Jamie Bowles, GS with G.I.s, GS on V.E. Day, group of children dressed for putting on a play, GS at rue Christine in Paris.
      See also: Oversize, Box 170, folder 4335 for GS, ABT and Basket II in horse-drawn carriage in the Bois de Boulogne
  - PHOTOGRAPHERS' PORTRAITS OF GERTRUDE STEIN
    - Cecil Beaton
      See: Oversize, Box 170, folder 4336
    - Thérèse Bonney, Paris, 1925?, 1932? (Box 152, Folder 3656-3659)
      Includes Virgil Thomson in one pose
    - Alvin Langdon Coburn, 1912-13 (Box 152, Folder 3660-3661)
    - Delar, New York, [1934?] (Box 152, Folder 3662)
      See also: Oversize, Box 171, folders 4337-4344
    - J. P. Graham, Del Monte, California, [1935?] (Box 152, Folder 3663-3666)
    - Ray Lee Jackson, New York, [1934] (Box 152, Folder 3667-3674)
      Includes ABT and William Lundell in several poses
    - George Platt Lynes, 1935 (Box 152, Folder 3675-3676)
      See also: Oversize, Box 170, folder 4336
    - Henri Manuel, 1924
    - Man Ray, 1920, 1922 (Box 152, Folder 3677-3681)
    - Unidentified, signed by GS, 1935
  - PHOTOGRAPHS REMOVED FROM INCOMING CORRESPONDENCE
    [Photographs are of the sender, unless noted]
    - Aldrich, Mildred, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3682)
      [photograph of man and a mule]
    - Bernadet, J. C., père, 1939 (Box 152, Folder 3683)
    - Bianco, Giovanni, 1945 (Box 152, Folder 3684)
    - Braque, Georges, ca. 1910 (Box 152, Folder 3685)
    - Bromfield, Louis, ca. 1939 (Box 152, Folder 3686)
    - Chapman, Elizabeth Fuller, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3687)
    - Draper, Benjamin [letter of 1939 Jul 5] (Box 152, Folder 3688)
    - Duncan, Winifred, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3689)
    - Favre, Louis, ca. 1921 (Box 152, Folder 3690)
      [photograph of painting of LF]
    - Faÿ, Bernard, 1933 (Box 152, Folder 3691)
    - Forquier, Raymond (Box 152, Folder 3692)
    - [Gassette, Grace ?], n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3693)
    - Glass, Douglas, ca. 1930 (Box 152, Folder 3694)
    - Gris, Juan, ca. 1910 (Box 152, Folder 3695)
    - Haas, Robert Bartlett, ca. 1938-39 (Box 152, Folder 3696-3698)
      [Photographs of RH and wife, Louise]
    - Hristodoulovitch, Juliette, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3699)
      [Photograph of Yves Hristodoulovitch]
    - Hugnet, Georges, ca. 1926-30 (Box 152, Folder 3700-3702)
      [Includes photograph of GS and of painting of GH by Christian Bérard]
    - Imbs, Bravig, ca. 1928 (Box 152, Folder 3703-3704)
      [Includes photograph of Valeska Imbs]
    - Lascaux, Elie, 1928 (Box 152, Folder 3705)
      [Photograph of Germaine Lascaux, infant daughter of EL]
    - Lebender, Lena, [ca. 1904?] (Box 152, Folder 3706)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3707)
    - Morris, George L. K. [letter of [1938] Apr 12], ca. 1938 (Box 152, Folder 3708-3709)
    - Picasso, Pablo, ca. 1925 (Box 152, Folder 3710)
      [Photograph of Picasso family]
    - Ronnebeck, Arnold [letter of 1913 Dec 6], ca. 1913 (Box 152, Folder 3711)
      [Photographs of aerial views of Paris]
    - Rose, Francis, Sir, 1945, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 3712-3716)
      [includes photographs of painting by Francis Rose]